<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Taekwondo</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="abrir">Open</string>
    <string name="cerrar">Close</string>
    <string name="entrar">Access</string>
    <string name="entrarcomoinvitado">Access as a guest</string>
    <string name="registrarse">Check in</string>
    <string name="olvidar">I forgot my password</string>
    <string name="recuperar">Recover my password</string>
    <string name="email">E-mail</string>
    <string name="pass">Password</string>
    <string name="bienvenida">W E L C O M E</string>
    <string name="bienvenida1">to the first Taekwondo application, created by taekwondo players for taekwondo players.</string>
    <string name="bienvenida2">You will love it ! !</string>
    <string name="federacion">Federations</string>
    <string name="reglamento">Regulation</string>
    <string name="historia">History</string>
    <string name="saludo">Greeting</string>
    <string name="ponercinturon">Place belt</string>
    <string name="nivelcituron">Belt levels</string>
    <string name="frases">Phrases</string>
    <string name="partesdelcuerpo">Body parts</string>
    <string name="terminologiabasica">Basic terms</string>
    <string name="galeria">Gallery</string>
    <string name="mapa">Map Gyms</string>
    <string name="tituloposicion">Positions</string>
    <string name="tituloataque">Attacks</string>
    <string name="titulodefensa">Defenses</string>
    <string name="titulopatada">Kicks</string>
    <string name="nombrecombinaciontecnicas">Combination of techniques</string>
    <string name="titulopum">Special moves</string>
    <string name="sobrenosotros">"About us "</string>
    <string name="terminologiacompeticion">Competition</string>
    <string name="terminologianumeros">Numbers</string>
    <string name="federacion1">World Taekwondo</string>
    <string name="federacion2">European Taekwondo Union</string>
    <string name="federacion3">Federation Spanish Taekwondo</string>
    <string name="botonreglamento">Download regulation arbitration</string>
    <string name="historia1">The ancestors of what currently is Korea, were organized in tribes, where are located incidios of Arts martial because paintings and murals.\n\n               They began with dances and religious rites, but they had to defend themselves against other tribes, so incorporated copied shipment of animals.\n\n              In the current South, dynasty Sil - Korea, is known from a few warriors specialized for their discipline and ferocity, which conquered various kingdoms. They highlighted the martial arts Tae Kyon and Do your Tang.         \n\n      In 1910 after the Japanese invasion, the practice of cultural events and sports non-Japanese (apesa r that practiced in the families in hiding) was prohibited.          \n\n     In 1945, after the end of the second world war, and despite the influence of Karate during 35anos, it rinicio the practice of Tae Kyon and Do your Tang.        \n\n       Through, Choi Hong Hee, a Korean military, trained soldiers in different martial arts. In 1955, was born the Taekwondo (the road of feet and fists), combining the best of different martial arts.    \n\n           Was founded in 1966 the ITF(International Taekwondo Federation y en 1970 la WTF (World Taekwondo Federation).) W.T.F. style continue if style of combat, but by believing himself to be influenced by Karate techniques were changed.           \n\n    In 1994, Taekwondo was accepted as Olympic sports for the Olympic Games of Sydney.    </string>
    <string name="sobrenosotros1">If you\'re reading this, it\'s because you\'re so loving taekwondo and enthusiastic as we of this martial art... :) \n Are Jessi and David, two students of 2nd degree, development of multi-platform applications, also known as DAM. \n Have been created non profit, with their own material, both images and text, based on knowledge acquired as an athlete more than 10 years. \n Us why we decided to create is APP after finding a hole in the lack of applications of this martial art, Taekwondo. \n Esperemos that you like, and serve you useful. You have a community at your disposal in order to improve it.</string>
    <string name="saludo1">The greeting is a demonstration of respect for the teacher and the rest of our colleagues. The greeting should not be just an empty gesture. By dint of repeating it over and over again this manifestation of respect becomes a spontaneous and sincere gesture that is expressed in the heart and that enriches life both of him who gives and who receives it.</string>
    <string name="saludo2">Such is the importance of greeting and its meaning, which in the course of a single class, this ritual is repeated many times:-before entering the Dojang. Ask permission to enter to the master or higher degree belt, and greet each other.  \n\n    At the beginning of the class. The largest student grade directs the corresponding protocol.\n\n      During the class. When you receive a training material and at the end of training with a partner.     \n\n At the end of the class. Students of higher level directs the corresponding protocol.  \n\n    Before to leave the Dojang. He greets looking at the Dojang.</string>
    <string name="ponercinturon1">1. place one side of the tip of the belt above the navel. \\n\\n 2 - hold the tip of the belt at the level of the navel, and return with the other side of the waist belt around your waist. \\n\\n 3 - with the excess belt wrapped around his waist. \\n\\n 4 - pass it over the first end. \\n\\n 5 - the tip of the belt that is left out, put it inside, below the fold of the belt and then up. \\n\\n 6 - prepare folded the bottom tip of the belt. \\n\\n 7 - put folded down the top of the belt. \\n\\n 8 - with both ends of the belt, make a knot, direction top down. Adjust the belt. \\n\\n 9 - coprobamos that the parties remaining tips are equally long on both sides. \\n</string>
    <string name="frase1">The true black belt is that white belt who never gave up.</string>
    <string name="frase2">In Taekwondo, fall is allowed, lift is required.</string>
    <string name="frase3">Taekwondo is not strength and speed, discipline and intelligence.</string>
    <string name="frase4">It doesn\'t matter if you kick a thousand times, it is important that you pateees only once and know that you hit you with the force of a thousand kicks.</string>
    <string name="frase5">What is my life? My passion? Would my being? The answer is very simple, the Taekwondo.</string>
    <string name="frase6">Die in training to live in combat.</string>
    <string name="frase7">No dream is impossible, while you keep maintaining the illusion of getting him.</string>
    <string name="frase8">The defeat today, is the seed of the victory of the morning.</string>
    <string name="frase9">The road is made by walking. Steadily, head high, attitude, work and heart.</string>
    <string name="frase10">Stronger, faster, higher.</string>
    <string name="partecuerpo1">\n Mori: head \n Mok: neck \n Nok: nose \n Bo: mouth \n Tok: chin \n Pal: arm \n Palkup: elbow \n Palmok: forearm \n Kut: fingers \n Chumok: fist \n Jori: hip \n Dari: leg \n \n
                                Son: hand \n Son Mok: doll \n Sonnal: singing the hand \n Son Kut: fingers of the hand \n Chumok me: fist singing \n \n
                                Bal: foot \n Bal Kut: toes \n Bal Mok: ankle \n Bal Dung: instep \n Bal Nal: foot ridge \n Bal Nal dung: inner foot ridge \n Ap Chuck: foot metatarsal \n Ti Chuck: heel \n Bal Badat: sole \n \n </string>
    <string name="mapaTextoFinal">If you want your gym to appear on this map you can apply through the following form.</string>
    <string name="significadoamarillo">Special moves</string>
    <string name="nivelcituron1">Grades in Taekwondo are divided into KUP, PUM and DAN. In Spain, there are 11 ° KUP, the most basic. They follow a numbering reverse to the level of the student, each grade is represented by a colour belt - Ti - with a symbolic meaning.    In the case of the KUP, the belts are white (11th KUP), white-yellow (10th KUP), yellow (9th KUP), yellow-orange (8th KUP), Orange (7th KUP), Orange (6th KUP), green (5th KUP), blue (4th KUP), blue (3rd KUP), blue (2nd KUP)-red, Red/Brown (1st KUP), Red-Black (1st KUM), and black (1st DAN).   Intermediate (two-color) degrees are only awarded to practitioners under the age of 14.</string>
    <string name="terminologiabasica1">\n Its 5 principles: Stoicism, Courage, Patience, Humility, Courtesy \n \n Sabomin: teacher \n Dochang: training place \n Dobok: Taekwondo suit \n Ti: belt \n
                                    Kiorugui: combat \n Chumbi: preparation \n Bon Kiorugui: prepared combat \n Duiro Dora: half-turn \n Kihap: scream (Ki-Energy / Hap-Aire \n Tea Guk Chag: greatness and eternity \n Pumse: defenses and combined attacks \n
                                    Are: lower body area \n Momotong: middle body area \n Olgul: Upper body area</string>
    <string name="terminologiacompeticion1">\n Chariot: firm, greeting \n Kionye position: greeting \n Chumbi: \n Sichak preparation: start \n Kesok: continue \n Kalio: spreading \n Kumna: end \n Jogu: peto \n Chong: Blue \n Hong: Red \n Sung: Victor \n Juecho: assault \n Kiongo: half a point less \n Kamchum: a point less \n Cha Yan Gu: face to face</string>
    <string name="mapaTextoInicial">Below is a map with the Taekwondo gyms</string>
    <string name="federaciontexto1">\n The Taekwondo world is the institution that dedicates itself to regulate the rules for the taekwondo at the competitive level, as well as periodically hold competitions and events in each of their disciplines. \n It is recognized by the International Olympic Committee. It is headquartered in the city of Seoul (South Korea). \n In the latest study, had the affiliation of 206 national federations (from the five continents), being one of the largest federations in the world in terms of national membership. \n Volume of practitioners is 73 million. \n Up to date became known as World Taekwondo Federation, but WTF are the abbreviation of the expression "What the fuck?", and whose use became popular on social networks to express surprise. Due to this fact, the World Taekwondo Federation decided to change in June 2017 its acronym, changing its name to World Taekwondo, English World Taekwondo (acronym: WT).   </string>
    <string name="federaciontexto2">\n The Union European Taekwondo is the institution that dedicates itself to regulate the rules of taekwondo in Europe, as well as periodically hold competitions and events in each of their disciplines. \n It is one of the five continental organisations that make up the World Taekwondo (WT).</string>
    <string name="federaciontexto3">\n Inside of the Union European of the Taekwondo, are located the Spanish Taekwondo Federation, composed of: Andalusian Federation, Aragonese Federation, Federation Asturiana, Federación Canaria Balearic Federation, Federation Cantabrian Federation Castilian Leonesa , Castilian-La Mancha Federation, Catalan Federation, Ceuta Federation, Federation of Basque country Federation Estremena, Galician Federation, Federation Madrid, Murcia Federation, Federación Navarra, Rioja Federation and Valencian Federation. </string>
    <string name="reglamentoTexto">\n Then can desacargarse the tropical of the Spanish Taekwondo Federation arbitajre (updated March 11, 2017)</string>
    <string name="reglamentoTexto2">\n Once downloaded, you can view it without entering the application, from its "internal memory of the phone", "TAE" folder.</string>
    <string name="historia2">But what is Taekwondo? \n Is a technique of body movements with the maximum power, balance, speed and accuracy. \n it is a sport, it is a way of life for its practitioners, is a discipline of mind and body. \n</string>
    <string name="salir">Exit</string>
    <string name="inicio">Home</string>
    <string name="amarillo">Yellow</string>
    <string name="cinturones">Belts</string>
    <string name="naranja">Orange</string>
    <string name="significadonaranja">Il symbolise la terre fertile, où être planté de nouvelles semences qui poussent comme plante future.</string>
    <string name="verde">Green</string>
    <string name="significadoverde">"It symbolises the germination of the seed, like a new plant. "</string>
    <string name="azul">Blue</string>
    <string name="significadoazul">"Symbolizes the sky, toward which grows the plant to become a mature tree, as advancing knowledge in Taekwondo. "</string>
    <string name="marron">Brown</string>
    <string name="significadomarron">It symbolizes the danger, it indicates their opponents that they should stay away, because of the maturity of their knowledge. \n Is the harvested fruit of the tree of the Taekwondo.</string>
    <string name="negro">Black</string>
    <string name="significadonegro">It symbolizes the maturity of the practitioner as to his competence to teach in the Taekwondo. Represents the impermeability of your carrier, the fear and darkness. It is completely the opposite of white.</string>
    <string name="ataqueamarillo1">\n A punch, an attack with the front part of the handle. \n Position of the rider, sitting horse. \n separation between the heels of 1 step. \n both knees bent and feet parallel between Sí. \n the body weight is distributed to 50%.</string>
    <string name="ataqueamarillo2">\n A double punch.</string>
    <string name="ataqueamarillo3">\n Front punch to the middle zone. \n	The fist hitting is the one corresponding to the front leg.</string>
    <string name="ataqueamarillo4">\n Front punch to the middle zone. \n The fist hitting is the one corresponding to the hind leg.</string>
    <string name="ataqueamarillo5">\n Double front punch to the middle zone. \n The first fist hitting is the corresponding to the hind leg, and the following fist to the front leg.</string>
    <string name="posicionamarillo1">\n Normal walking short, step step. \n  The feet form an internal angle of 15 ° to 30 °. \n The weight of the body is provided, the Centre of gravity falls between two toes.</string>
    <string name="posicionamarillo2">\n A long step. \n The front knee should be bent and the rear leg straight. \n The feet form an internal angle of 30 °. \n The body weight is distributed 2/3 parts front and 1/3 part back.</string>
    <string name="posicionamarillo3">\n Standing at attention. \n The ankles and heels must be in contact, and the tips of toes separated. \n Angle between the foot of 45º.</string>
    <string name="posicionamarillo4">\n  Position of the rider, sitting on horseback. \n Separation between the heels of 1 step. \n Both knees bent and feet parallel each other. \n The body weight is distributed to 50%.</string>
    <string name="defensaamarillo1">\n Low zone defense, diverts kicked and punched. \n Load the defense by placing the base of the handle on the opposite shoulder. \n Arm slips from the area of the shoulder down, covering the area pointing to the front.</string>
    <string name="defensaamarillo2">\n Low zone defense, diverts kicked and punched. \n Load the defense by placing the base of the handle on the opposite shoulder.  \n Arm slips from the area of the shoulder down, covering the area pointing to the front.</string>
    <string name="defensaamarillo3">\n Momtong-Maki like defense. \n Arm defending is the backward leg. \n Performs block from the outside towards the inside. </string>
    <string name="defensaamarillo4">\n Upper zone defense. \n Load the defense from the area of the hip. \n Arm rises in the area of the hip (low zone) to the upper area of the body.</string>
    <string name="defensaamarillo5">Middle zone defence. Load the defense in the same way as Olgul Maki, from the area of the hip. Use the outside of the wrist to screen out. </string>
    <string name="posicionamarillo5">Preparation position. The distance between the grips and the belt, is a fist.</string>
    <string name="patadaamarillo1">\n Kick front to rise as high as possible, delayed knee. \n Struck with the pad of the foot (Ap Chuk)</string>
    <string name="patadaamarillo2">\n Quick circular kick. \n  Loaded by placing the knee in an arc parallel to the ground. It launches out in circular motion. \n You strike with the instep of the foot (Bal Dung)</string>
    <string name="patadaamarillo3">\n Side kick. \n  It pivots the support foot, hitting at the same time with the edge of the foot, heel (Ti Chuk), nailing the thumbs-down.</string>
    <string name="patadaamarillo4">\n Kick axe, down. \n load lifting mode front forward leg. Is made lower leg, hitting with the sole of the foot (Bal Badat)</string>
    <string name="pumseamarillo1">\n It represents the sky and the light. \n Composed of 18 sequences.</string>
    <string name="idioma">Language:</string>
    <string name="posicionnaranja1">\n Comparison between heels is a step. Heels in line, forming the foot 90° between them. \n Rear knee bent, focusing the Centre of gravity. \n Hind leg supports 70% of the weight, the front leg supports 30% of the weight.</string>
    <string name="ataquenaranja1">\n Triple punch. \n The first two punches are aimed to the middle zone, the third to the base of the nose.</string>
    <string name="ataquenaranja2">\n Blow to the neck with both hands open and palms up. \n Loaded with open hands and elbows bent. \n Struck with the edge of the hand, leaving these up.</string>
    <string name="ataquenaranja3">\n Release with the fist vertical and the thumbs-up.</string>
    <string name="ataquenaranja4">\n Attack on the neck with the edge of the hand, corresponding to the late foot. \n Attack from outside to the inside, with the Palm of the hand facing up.</string>
    <string name="ataquenaranja5">\n Attack on the neck area. \n Attacks with the edge of the hand, inside out, with the Palm of the hand facing up.</string>
    <string name="ataquenaranja6">\n As Momotong Bande Jirugui, but uptown (Olgul). \n Struck with the fist of the forward leg, to Uptown.</string>
    <string name="defensanaranja1">\n Defense zone media. \n The Palm of the hand is situated facing the opponent. \n The blockade is supporting the big toe with the index finger. </string>
    <string name="patadanaranja1">\nCircular kick towards inside. \n Hits with the outer edge of the foot.</string>
    <string name="patadanaranja2">\n Circular kick out. \n Is hit with the inner half of the sole of the foot.</string>
    <string name="patadanaranja3">\n Kick back. \n Extends the heel of the foot hitting to an opoente that is behind us.</string>
    <string name="pumsenaranja1">\n It is the joy, jubilation. \n Composed of 18 sequences.</string>
    <string name="pumsenaranja2">\n What distinguishes man from the animal, is as it should be used the fire. \n Composed of 20 sequence.</string>
    <string name="posicionverde1">\n Feet in L, looking towards the right. \n a foot between feet separation.</string>
    <string name="posicionverde2">\n Feet in L, looking toward the left. \n a foot between feet separation.</string>
    <string name="ataqueverde1">\n Hit to the middle zone, with both hands open and palms facing up. \n Technical as Du Sonnal Mok Chigui, but to the middle of the body.</string>
    <string name="ataqueverde2">\n Attack in short distance, at the base of the ribs. \n Double attack in the form of hook, with fists up.</string>
    <string name="ataqueverde3">\n Attack on the area of the ribs. \n Is hit with the tip of the fingers (known as Pion are Kut). \n The palm of the hand is in portrait mode to the attack.</string>
    <string name="ataqueverde4">\n Attack on the upper lip or forehead. \n Is hit with the back of the fist (known as are Dung). \n Is in tension, the elbow slightly bent.</string>
    <string name="defensaverde1">\n Defense of the area media. \n Is blocked with the edge of the hand, with a lateral motion of the interior to the extaerior. \n One hand protects at the height of the sternum, the other tour, ending in a higher position.</string>
    <string name="pumverde1">\n Simultaneous movement of attack and defense. \n tTe edge of the hand of the forward leg defends the face. \n The other hand singing, attacks the opponent\'s neck, from outside to inside. \n One hand protects at the height of the sternum, another tour ending in a higher position.</string>
    <string name="patadaverde1">\n It is a kick turn, simulating a hook. \n Foot hitting launches in the arc parallel to the ground.</string>
    <string name="patadaverde2">\n Yop Chagüi kick, but with body rotation.</string>
    <string name="patadaverde3">\n The body rotates 360°. \n Attacks to the face, with the inner part of the foot. \n Requires balance and speed.</string>
    <string name="pumseverde1"> Symbolizes Thunder, stimulating fear, fear of the unknown, the tromenta. \n composed of 20 movements.</string>
</resources>